Setumadhava Giridhar Kathawate

Product Designer With A Passion For Solving People's Problems.

206-739-4983 setugk8@gmail.com Atlanta, GA <u>www.setumadhava.com</u>

About

Product designer having 3 years of experience in designing products, seeking opportunities to solve complex user and business problems through elegant, research-informed product and experience designs. Other interests include Machine Learning, Behavioral Psychology, and Cooking.

Skills

Primary UX Skills: Interaction design, Prototyping, Visual design, Framer, InVision, Sketch, Product strategy, Project scoping, Cross-functional collaboration, Agile development process, Remote and inperson user research methods, Usability studies, HTML/CSS/JS.

Meta Skills: Awareness, Responsibility and Ownership, Integrity, Decision making, Resourceful, Critical thinking, Problem-solving, Constant learning.

Experience

UX DESIGNER, THE HOME DEPOT (VIA SYNERGIS)

APR 2018 - PRESENT

Leading design initiatives to optimize work flows of floor managers and employees to make better decisions and improve efficiency at The Home Depot's distribution and fulfillment centers.

Responsibilities: User research, journey mapping, interviews, data synthesis, wire-framing, project scoping, cross-functional collaboration, user interface & interaction design, usability testing.

UX DESIGNER, UW MEDICINE (VIA CREATIVE CIRCLE)

DEC 2017 - MAR 2018

Designed web and mobile experiences as a part of UW Medicine's website redesign efforts.

Key Accomplishment: Owned the responsibility and delivered 14 high-fidelity, production-ready web and mobile screen mockups in 2 days, after the contracted design agency failed to deliver the designs on-time. As a result, there was no delay in the project timelines.

CO-FOUNDER AND PRODUCT DESIGNER, EVENTOSAUR

MAR 2015 - PRESENT

Leading a distributed team of designers and non-designers to build a SaaS product to solve the problem of order, inventory and team management for event vendors in India.

Key Accomplishment: Co-founded a profitable event-planning start-up and worked remotely while in grad school to design a web-app that solved the problem of vendor discovery and reduced the complexity in traditional event planning for millennials in India.

UX DESIGNER, PREMERA BLUE CROSS (VIA FILTER DIGITAL)

MAY 2017 - DEC 2017

Led the UX efforts to design a Provider Search tool to help Premera's customers confidently find the providers or facilities covered by their insurance plan.

Key Accomplishment: Average customer satisfaction score went up from 2.8 to 4.1 (on a scale of 1-5) after shipping the new search experience.

Education

MASTER'S IN HUMAN CENTERED DESIGN AND ENGINEERING

SEP 2015 - MAR 2017

The University of Washington, Seattle; GPA 3.92/4.0

Relevant Courses: User-Centered Design, Usability Studies, Data Science for UX Researchers, Visual Communication, Interaction Design and Prototyping.

BACHELOR'S IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING

AUG 2006 - JUN 2010

Visvesvaraya Technological University, Bangalore, India; GPA 6.9/10.0

Awards

BEST GRADUATE CAPSTONE PROJECT - PUMP IT UP

JUN 2017

University of Washington, Seattle

Explored design solutions to reduce water waste in Indian homes by designing an Android app + IOT system that provides contextual information and better control over existing water systems to the residents.